

PHYSICIST & PHYSICS TEACHER

9129 Main St, Westernville NY 13486

□+1-315-532-0278 |
| jeffrey.p.hafner@gmail.com | # jphafner.github.io | □ jphafner | □ jphafner

I am a geek, a skeptic and I wear bowties for fun. I have been a physics teacher for two years, and been a Unix Engineer for two years, and was described on my 2017 performance review as highly innovative. This is due to my boundless energy, that seeks out a solution to everything.

Experience ____

Unix Linux Systems Engineer

New York, NY

Aug 2016-Mar 2018

IPSOFT INC

- Manage IT infrastructure of high profile clients
- Monitored client environments and developed automation to resolve issue
- Provided automation to clients using Ansible, for example patching
- Had commendable communication with key clients, McKesson

Physics Teacher Dobbs Ferry, NY

Masters School

- Teaching 11th grade and AP Physics B Mechanics
- An example lesson plan and lab report template used
- · Utilized a unique assessment system that allowed infinite redos

Physics Teacher Baltimore, MD

BALTIMORE CITY PUBLIC SCHOOLS

Dullillore, MD

2014-2015

2015-2016

- Teaching physics first at Mervo
- · Utilized a unique assessment system that allowed infinite redos

Education

University at Buffalo Buffalo, NY

PH.D IN PHYSICSAug. 2006 – Feb. 2012

Andrews University Berrien Springs, MI

B.S./M.S. IN BIOPHYSICS AND MATHEMATICAL STUDIES Aug. 2001 – Aug. 2006

Projects_

physicsAMC

PHYSICS TEACHER multiple locations

2014-2016

- A comprehensive physics exam bank that utilizes an Ipeg parser for question selection.
- This project enabled me to use an infinite redo policy on all assessments, without punishment, which was an important motivation for this project, and created some of my favorite memories.
- this project utilizes LTFX, lua, lpeg, and tikz for graphics, and contains more than a 100,000 lines of code.
- sample-exam

Publications

2009	Approximate normal mode analysis based on vibrational subsystem analysis with high accuracy and	Hafner J. & Zheng
	efficiency, Journal of Chemical Physics	W.
2010	Optimal modeling of atomic fluctuations in protein crystal structures for weak crystal contact interactions,	Hafner J. & Zheng
	Journal of Chemical Physics	W.
2011	All-atom modeling of anisotropic atomic fluctuations in protein crystal structures, Journal of Chemical	Hafner J. & Zheng
	Physics	W.